## JOSÉ ALBERTO LÓPEZ LÓPEZ

# BACHELORS IN PHYSICS MASTERS IN ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

✓ JLL.6@hotmail.com

#### **ABOUT ME**

Artificial Intelligence developer with experience in various languages and frameworks. I have worked in big data projects using real time transmission technologies and several data science projects as well. I consider myself a dedicated, responsable and very capable person.

#### **EXPERIENCE**



#### **Artificial Intelligence Developer**

GRUPO SALINAS · Ciudad de México, Mexico dec 2021 – aug 2022

Big data AI developer in projects related to bank credit fraud prevention, using tools like Spark, Hadoop, Kafka, among others.



#### **Data Scientist**

MIGALA · Ciudad de México, Mexico dec 2021 – feb 2022

Data analysis of an inquest realized to potential members of a new political party. Foundations of a Blockchain project with Solidity and other components.



#### **Data Scientist**

BEST PRACTICES CONSULTING · Querétaro, Mexico

mar 2021 - sep 2021

Data visualizations designer with Power BI for several companies projects, including a dashboard with information about gas distribution routes in real time.



## **Algorithms and Prototipes Developer**

ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE RESEARCH CENTER

· University of Veracruz, Mexico
jun 2016 – jun 2017

C++ developer of an autonomous movement vehicle detection algorithm, designed for an embedded system, using accelerometers and Furier analisys.

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

	Junior	Senior
Python		
C++		
SQL		
Java		
Solidity		
HTML, CSS		
Javascript		
Others		

#### FRAMEWORKS & SYSTEMS

Spark	
MongoDB	
Kafka	
Hadoop	
Git	
Blockchain	
Azure	
Docker	
Kubernetes	

#### COMPLEMENTARY EXPERIENCE

- Experience in Keras and TensorFlow for deep learning and machine learning.
- Knowledge of dense, convolutional, and recurrent neural networks; as well as evolutionary and nature-inspired algorithms.
- Computer vision with OpenCV library in C++ and Python.
- Experience in parallel programing with OpenMS and MSI libraries in C and C++.
- Experience working with data science applied to geographical and cities databases.
- Large experience in data visualization with Matplotlib, Gnuplot, TikZ-PGF and Power Bl.
- Mathematical foundations of models for time series analisys, like ARIMA, SARIMA, VARMA, Dickey-Fuller test, Granger causality, Holt-Winters method, EWMA, ETS, Hodrick-Prescott filter, etc.
- Robotic Operative System (ROS) with C++ and Python.

#### **EDUCATION**

### 2020 Masters in artificial intelligence

ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE RESEARCH CENTER · University of Veracruz, Mexico in

#### 2018 Bachelors in physics

FACULTY OF PHYSICS · University of Veracruz, Mexico im

Best marks of generation.

#### LANGUAGES

**Spanish** Native

#### COURSES

Institute	Subject	ID and URL
Udemy	Docker & Kubernetes	C
MongoDB Academy	MongoDB	
Udemy	Blockchain	C
Udemy	Time Series Data Analisis	C
Udemy	Git	C
Udemy	SQL: Basic to Advanced	C
SoloLearn	SQL	C
SoloLearn	Java	C

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Robot Hostess D

I programmed the entire code of a Robot hostess in C++ with ROS. The robot detects diners via face recognition and lead them to a suitable table.

#### Augmented reality

Example of augmented reality made with Python and OpenCV.

## Traveling salesman problem visualization D Visualization of traveling salesman problem solved

with simulated annealing.

#### **Grasp Objects in Clutter (Masters Thesis)**

I developed an algorithm for accommodate objects in order to facilitating later grasps by appling Al nature inspired algorithms.

#### CONTACT

☑ JLL.6@hotmail.com

**1** +52 228-105-4832

**\( +52 296-964-7471** 

in Alberto López

#### REFERENCES

#### Marxlenin Zapata Yañez

Chief of Reactor Engineering department at Laguna Verde Nuclear Power Plant.

Relation: Previous boss.

☐ marxlenin.zapata@cfe.gob.mx

## Irving Morales Agiss, PhD

Director of data science MORLANmx enterprise.

Relation: Professor.

☑ irvingfisica@gmail.com

#### Antonio Marín Hernández, PhD

Researcher at the Artificial Intelligence Research Center of University of Veracruz, Mexico.

Relation: Thesis assesor.

☑ anmarin@uv.mx